Register of the Ardashīr Zāhidī papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Photographs, circa 1915-2000s
  - Albums, circa 1920s-1978
    - Mohammad Reza Pahlavi receiving honorary degree from American University, 1973 (Box 194, Folder 1)
    - State visit, 1973 (Box 258)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir, the Shah, Richard Nixon, William P. Rogers, Henry Kissinger, and Asadollah Alam.
    - White House state visit, 1973 (Box 195)
      Includes photographs of Pat and Richard Nixon, Spiro Agnew, William P. Rogers, and Farah and Mohammad Reza Pahlavi.
    - Tour of Hughes Aircraft Company, 1973 (Box 194, Folder 2)
    - Yacht tour, circa 1973 (Box 194, Folder 3)
    - Epping Forest, Jacksonville, Florida, 1973 May 18 (Box 194, Folder 4)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir and Henry M. Jackson.
    - Luncheon in honor of the Sheikh of Sharjah, 1973 June 13 (Box 194, Folder 5)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir, Sultan bin Muhammad Al-Qasimi, Harold H. Saunders, Ibrahim Al-Sowayel, and J. William Fulbright.
    - Kerr-McGee Operations tour, 1973 August 18-19 (Box 251)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir with Gholam H. Kazemian, Dean Krakel, Patience Latting, Dean McGee, and Bill Stevens.
    - East Texas State University commencement, 1973 August (Box 194, Folder 6)
      Includes clippings and letter, and photographs of Ardeshir and F. H. "Bub" McDowell.
    - Imperial Iranian Ships IIS Babr and IIS Palang, 1973 October 12 (Box 194, Folder 7)
    - Expo '74: Spokane World's Fair, 1974 May-July (Box 194, Folder 8)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir and Richard Nixon, as well as photographs of Iranian National Holiday celebrations.
    - Visit to University of Southern California, 1974 August 22 (Box 194, Folder 9)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir, Abbas Ghaffari, Gholam H. Kazemian, and Dr. John R. Hubbard.
    - Kent State University commencement, 1974 August 31 (Boxes 193, 195)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir, Yousef Akbar, Fay R. Biles, Abbas Ghaffari, John Goodlad, Gholam H. Kazemian, Edgar Mitchell, Glenn A. Olds, Nader Pahldad, and Charles J. Pilliod Jr.
    - Birthday, 1974 October 16 (Box 195)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir, Joan and Tom Braden, Ed Brooke, Henry and Jessica Catto, Betty and J. William Fulbright, William Shawcross, and Frank and Kandy Stroud.
    - Visit to Grumman Corporation, 1974 November 4 (Box 196, Folder 1)
    - Reception for the Council on Younger Lawyers, 1974 November 15-21 (Box 196, Folder 2)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir and Penelope S. Farthing.
    - Tour of Hughes Aircraft Company, 1974 November 23 (Box 257)
    - State visit, 1975 May (Box 258)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir, Farah and Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, Betty and Gerald Ford, and Happy and Nelson Rockefeller.
    - White House state visit album, 1975 May 15-16 (Box 259)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir, Farah and Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, Betty and Gerald Ford, Happy and Nelson Rockefeller, and Henry Kissinger.
    - Black tie dinner dance for the Shahbanu of Iran, 1975 July 8 (Box 196)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir, Farah Pahlavi, Henry Kissinger, Rudolf Nureyev, Edward Kennedy, Fereydoun Hoveyda, Abbas Ghaffari, and Gholam H. Kazemian.
    - Event at embassy, 1975 October (Box 196)
    - Race for Life, 1976 (Box 196, Folder 3)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir and Elizabeth Taylor.
    - Inaugural flight: Iran Air, New York to Tehran, 1976 May (Box 258)
      Consists of photographs and letters from those who visited Iran, including Elizabeth Taylor. Album presented by Mehdi Omana.
    - Westminster College Alumni Homecoming and 34th John Findley Green Lecture, 1977 May (Box 196, Folder 4)
    - Valley Forge Military Academy, 1977 May (Box 196, Folder 5)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir, Nancy and Strom Thurmond, Willard Pearson, Bob Hope, and General Mataxis.
    - Convocation at Howard University, 1977 May 14 (Box 197, Folder 1)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir and James E. Cheek.
    - Visit to San Diego and Los Angeles, 1977 December (Box 197, Folder 2)
      Includes letter frm Mehdi Omana.
    - Ardeshir Zahedi with Farah Pahlavi, circa 1977-1978 (Box 197, Folder 3)
    - Care Committee, 1973-1978 (Box 197, Folder 4)
    - Dedication ceremony of the 80th IIAF F-14 Tomcat, 1978 (Box 197, Folder 5)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir, Ali Reza Pahlavi, Jack Bierwirth, and George Skurla at Grumman Corporation.
  - Embassy albums, 1973-1978
    These albums, arranged chrologically, largely document social events hosted by Ardeshir Zahedi at the Iranian Embassy. Events include dinners and parties given for diplomats, politicians (American and Iranian), military officials, holidays, and members of the Pahlavi family.
    The following people appear in multiple albums: Yousef Akbar, George Allen, Pearl Bailey, Birch and Marvella Bayh, Edward Brooke, Bunny and Philip W. Buchen, Mr. and Mrs. Henry Catto, Huang Chen, Deena Clark, Mr. and Mrs. Marshall Coyne, Arlene Dahl, Ymelda Dixon, Sidney Epstein, Abbas Ghaffari, Barry Goldwater, Bill Graves, Joanne Herring, Fereydoon Hoveyda, Jacob K. Javits, Gholam H. Kazemian, Edward Kennedy, Begum and Sahabzada Yaqub Khan, Henry and Nancy Kissinger, Jacques Kosciusko-Morizet, Irving Levine, Mr. and Mrs. Clark MacGregor, Peter Malatesta, Mike Mansfield, Mara and Sylvan Marshall, J. William Middendorf, Julie Newmar, José Juan de Olloqui, Charles and Lorraine Percy, Frances and Peter Ramsbotham, Abraham and Casey Ribicoff, Adele and William P. Rogers, Mr. and Mrs. Carl Rowan, Jane and Kenneth Rush, Abdullah Salah, David Schoumacher, Count and Countess de Segonzac, Marion H. Smoak, Garnett Stackelberg, Helen and Robert S. Strauss, Stuart Symington, Wilhelm Wachtmeister, Bennetta and Walter Washington, and Miss Yazdan-Panah.
    - National Day 1973 - Foreign (Box 198, Folder 1-2)
    - Black tie dinner in honor of Joan Fontaine, 1973 May 14 (Box 198, Folder 3-4)
    - Black tie dinner given by Barry Goldwater at the Georgetown Club, circa 1974 (Box 198, Folder 5)
      Includes photographs of Gerald Ford.
    - Black tie dinner for the Honorable and Mrs. William Rogers, 1974 February (Box 198, Folder 6-8)
    - Black tie dinner for His Excellency Huang Chen, 1974 June 25 (Box 198, Folder 9-12)
    - Black tie dinner for Senator and Mrs. William Fulbright, 1974 July 30 (Box 199, Folder 1-4)
      Includes photographs of John B. Anderson, Jonathan and June Bingham, Frank Church, John Sherman Cooper, Clifton Daniel, Daryoush Homayoun, Endre Marton, Charles Mathias, B. K. Roberts, Paul Rogers, Mr. and Mrs. Scowcraft, John Sparkman, and Kandy Stroud.
    - Black tie dinner for Senator and Mrs. George Aiken, 1974 September 10 (Box 199, Folder 5-9)
      Includes photographs of Mr. and Mrs. Ellsworth Bunker, Melvin Laird, Glenn A. Olds, Helen Thomas, and Jack and Mary Margaret Valenti.
    - Black tie farewell dinner for Ambassador and Mrs. Badreddine Senoussi of Morocco, 1974 (Box 199, Folder 10-13)
      Includes photographs of Margot Fonteyn.
    - Black tie dinner for His Excellency and Mrs. Hushang Ansary, 1974 October 3 (Box 200, Folder 1-4, Box 199, Folder 14)
    - National Day 1974 - Persian, 1974 October 26 (Box 200, Folder 5-8)
      "Reception on the Occasion of His Imperial Majesty's Birthday."
    - National Day 1974 - Foreign, 1974 October 26 (Box 200, Folder 9-12, Box 201, Folder 1)
    - Black tie dinner for the Honorable and Mrs. Kenneth Rush, 1974 November 4 (Box 201, Folder 2-6)
    - Black tie dinner for Elliott Richardson, 1975 February 12 (Box 201, Folder 7-10)
    - Dinner for Dr. and Mrs. Joseph Sisco, 1975 March (Box 202, Folder 1-2, Box 201, Folder 11)
    - Black tie dinner for His Excellency Hushang Ansary, 1975 March (Box 202, Folder 3-6)
    - Charity gala evening, 1975 March 13 (Box 202, Folder 7-10)
      Includes photographs of Rose Kennedy and Barbra Streisand.
    - Nowruz party at the Sheraton Hotel, 1975 March 21 (Box 202, Folder 11-13)
    - Black tie dinner for Senator and Mrs. John Sparkman, 1975 April 15 (Box 203, Folder 1-3)
    - Royal visit (Box 203, Folder 4-10)
      Includes photographs of Farah and Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, Betty and Gerald Ford, Barbara Walters, and Mikhail Baryshnikov.
    - Black tie dinner for Dr. and Mrs. Manouchehr Eghbal, 1975 May 23 (Box 203, Folder 11-13)
    - Black tie dinner dance for Her Imperial Majesty the Shahbanu of Iran, 1975 July 8 (Box 204, Folder 1-3)
      Includes photos of Farah Pahlavi and Rudolf Nureyev.
    - Black tie dinner for Town & Country, 1975 September (Box 204, Folder 4-7)
    - National Day 1975 - Persian, 1975 October (Box 204, Folder 8-11)
    - National Day 1975 - Foreign, 1975 October (Box 205, Folder 1-6)
    - Black tie dinner for Sir Clive, 1975 October 21 (Box 205, Folder 7-9)
    - Black tie dinner for Imperial Iranian Navy Commander-in-Chief, 1975 December (Box 205, Folder 10-13)
    - Black tie dinner for General Hassan Toufanian, 1976 January 21 (Box 206, Folder 1-4)
    - Black tie dinner for Maury Povich, 1976 January 30 (Box 206, Folder 5-7)
    - Abbas Ghaffari's wedding, 1976 February (Box 206, Folder 8-10)
    - Valentine's Day party in honor of Julius Goodman, 1976 February 14 (Box 206, Folder 11-12, Box 207, Folder 1-2)
    - Dinner in honor of the American governors, 1976 February 22 (Box 207, Folder 3-5)
    - Black tie dinner for Her Imperial Highness Princess Ashraf Pahlavi, 1976 February 25 (Box 207, Folder 6-9)
    - Reception for the Aspen Persepolis Group, 1976 March 6 (Box 207, Folder 10-12)
    - Nowruz party at the Sheraton Hotel, 1976 March (Box 208, Folder 1-4)
    - Nowruz reception, 1976 March (Box 208, Folder 5-7)
    - Reception for the President of the Senate of the Bahamas, 1976 April (Box 208, Folder 8-10)
    - Black tie dinner for the American Ballet Theater, 1976 April 6 (Box 208, Folder 11, Box 209, Folder 1-3)
      Includes photographs of Mikhail Baryshnikov, Liza Minelli, Rudolf Nureyev, and Elizabeth Taylor.
    - Black tie dinner for Senator and Mrs. Mike Mansfield, 1976 May 7 (Box 209, Folder 4-7)
      Includes photographs of Elizabeth Taylor.
    - Iran Air inaugural non-stop flight to Tehran, 1976 May 15 (Box 209, Folder 8-11)
    - Black tie dinner for the Honorable and Mrs. William Scranton/Senator Stuart Symington, 1976 May 26 (Box 210, Folder 1-2, Box 209, Folder 12-13)
    - Black tie dinner for the Honorable and Mrs. Carlisle Humelsine, President of Colonial Williamsburg, 1976 June 8 (Box 210, Folder 3-6)
    - Black tie dinner in honor of the Chancellor of Tehran University and Mrs. Hushang Nahavandi, 1976 June 16 (Box 210, Folder 7-10)
    - Black tie dinner dance for Her Imperial Highness Princess Shams Pahlavi, 1976 (Box 211, Folder 1-2, Box 210, Folder 11-13)
      Includes photographs of Fawzia.
    - Staff presentation, 1976 (Box 211, Folder 3-4)
    - Black tie dinner for National Geographic group, 1976 October 15 (Box 211, Folder 5-6)
    - Exhibition of Mahmoud Farshchian's paintings at the Middle East Institute, 1976 October 19 (Box 211, Folder 7-9)
    - National Day 1976 - Foreign, 1976 October 26 (Box 211, Folder 10-13, Box 212, Folder 1-2)
      Includes photographs of Shirley Temple.
    - National Day 1976 - Persian, 1976 October 27 (Box 212, Folder 3-6)
    - International Management and Development Institute luncheon at the Embassy, 1976 November 11 (Box 212, Folder 7)
    - Black tie dinner for CARE, 1976 November 19 (Box 212, Folder 8-10)
    - Kappa Sigma Man of the Year dinner, 1976 December 12 (Box 212, Folder 11-12)
    - Reception for Mr. Sylvan Marshall, 1976 December 13 (Box 213, Folder 1-3)
    - Black tie dinner in honor of Secretary of State and Mrs. Henry Kissinger, 1977 January 14 (Box 213, Folder 4-7)
    - Informal dinner in honor of Princess Shams, 1977 February 2 (Box 213, Folder 8-10)
    - Informal dinner for Andy Warhol, 1977 February 14 (Box 214, Folder 1-2, Box 213, Folder 11-12)
    - Nowruz party, 1977 March 20 (Box 214, Folder 3-7)
    - Informal dinner for the group responsible for the release of the hostages during the Hanafi Siege in Washington, 1977 April 11 (Box 214, Folder 8-10)
    - Reception for AFRICARE, 1977 April 17 (Box 214, Folder 11-13)
    - Wedding of Mr. and Mrs. Homayoun Mirza, 1977 May 6 (Box 215, Folder 1-2)
    - Black tie dinner for Dr. and Mrs. Henry Kissinger, 1977 May 10 (Box 215, Folder 3-7)
    - Black tie dinner for Secretary of the Interior and Mrs. Cecil Andrus, 1977 May 20 (Box 215, Folder 8-10)
    - Opening of the Haden-Zand Gallery, 1977 June 14 (Box 216, Folder 1-2, Box 215, Folder 11-12)
      Includes photographs of Fred Haden, Andy Warhol, and Homa Zand.
    - Black tie dinner for General and Mrs. Hassan Toufanian, 1977 June 22 (Box 216, Folder 3-4)
    - Iran Night at the National Press Club, 1977 June 23 (Box 216, Folder 5-6)
    - Kappa Sigma reception at the embassy, 1977 June 26 (Box 216, Folder 7)
    - Her Imperial Majesty receiving the embassy staff, 1977 July 11 (Box 216, Folder 8)
    - Black tie dinner on the occasion of the visit of Her Imperial Majesty, 1977 July 11 (Box 216, Folder 9-12)
      Includes photographs of Farah Pahlavi and Lily Amir-Arjomand.
    - Reception at the embassy following Her Majesty's visit, 1977 July 13 (Box 217, Folder 1-2)
    - Black tie dinner in honor of the Secretary of the Air Force and Mrs. John Stetson, 1977 July 14 (Box 217, Folder 3-4)
    - Black tie dinner for the Honorable and Mrs. Philip Buchen, 1977 September 20 (Box 217, Folder 5-7)
      Includes photographs of Mr. and Mrs. David Acheson, Mr. and Mrs. Tammenoms Bakker, Mr. and Mrs. J. Carter Brown, Mr. and Mrs. Roberto Gaja, Gretchen and William Gorog, Carla and Roderick Hills, Mr. and Mrs. Clark MacGregor, Lewis and Josephine Powell, Renee and Wallace H. Robinson, Mr. and Mrs. Edward Schmults, Filene Shouse, Mr. and Mrs. Roger Stevens, Elizabeth Taylor, and Mr. and Mrs. William Whyte.
    - Black tie dinner for His Excellency and Mrs. Hushang Ansary, 1977 September 27 (Box 217, Folder 8-11)
      Includes photographs of Cyrus A. Ansary, Lucy Bensen, Mr. and Mrs. John Brademas, Mr. and Mrs. Gene Bradley, Arthur and Helen Burns, Emine Esenbel, Denis and Edna Healey, Margaret and Peter Jay, Mr. and Mrs. J. Burke Knapp, Hugo B. Margáin, Charles and Rita Schultze, James Symington, David Suratgar, Johannes and Liesbeth Witteveen, and Philip and Marie-Lou de Zulueta.
    - Black tie dinner for the Foreign Minister of Turkey and Mrs. İhsan Sabri Çağlayangil, 1977 October 10 (Box 217, Folder 12-13)
      Includes photographs of Beryl and Lloyd Bentsen, Nancy Collins, Bill Cook, Mr. and Mrs. Evan Dobelle, Mr. and Mrs. Howard Fish, Mr. and Mrs. Philip L. Geyelin, Bo and Mab Goldman, Philip Habib, Antoinette and Mark Hatfield, Robert Hunter, Mr. and Mrs. Üner Kırdar, Kappy and William Leonard, George and Helen Mahon, Gillespie V. Montgomery, Joseph J. Sisco, Elizabeth Taylor, Mr. and Mrs. İlter Türkmen, and Clement Zablocki.
    - Black tie dinner for the Young Presidents' Organization, 1977 October 13 (Box 218, Folder 1)
    - Cocktails for the Peanut Brigade Group from Georgia, 1977 October 15 (Box 218, Folder 2-4)
    - Zodiac party at the Chevy Chase Club, jointly hosted by Ambassador Zahedi and Mrs. Philip Buchen, 1977 October 19 (Box 218, Folder 5-7)
      Includes photographs of Mr. and Mrs. David Acheson, Charles Bartlett, Clare Boothe Luce, Lewis Powell, Mr. and Mrs. Potter Stewart, and Mr. and Mrs. William Whyte.
    - National Day - Foreign, 1977 October 26 (Box 218, Folder 8-13)
      Includes photographs of Timothee N'Guetta Ahoua, Joy Billington, Mr. and Mrs. Barnee Breeskin, Susan Clough, Kit Dobelle, George Englund, Chérif Guellal, Mr. and Mrs. Jim Hartz, Richard Helms, Anthony Hope, Reginald H. Jones, Abdul Waheed Karim, Mr. and Mrs. Walter Levy, Marjorie Margolies, Dr. and Mrs. Glenn A. Olds, Dorothy Padgett, Max Robinson, Mr. and Mrs. Stuart Rockwell, Dana Adams Schmidt, Lawrence E. Spivak, Robert Strauss, Stansfield Turner, John Wallach, and Mr. and Mrs. Barry ZeVan.
    - Black tie dinner in honor of the Chief of the Liaison Office of the People's Republic of China Huang Chen and Madame Chu Lin, 1977 November 1 (Box 219, Folder 1-2)
      Includes photographs of Lucy Benson, Mr. and Mrs. David Brinkley, Evangeline Bruce, Mr. and Mrs. Marquis Childs, Mary Hoyt, Han Hsu, Mr. and Mrs. Frank Ikard, Mr. and Mrs. Bernard Kalb, Mr. and Mrs. Michel Oksenberg, Mr. and Mrs. Dan Rather, Brent Scowcroft, and Richard Valeriani.
    - His Majesty meeting with the U.S.-Iran Business Council, 1977 November 14 (Box 219, Folder 3)
      Includes photographs of Farah and Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, Walter MacDonald, and Tom Brokaw.
    - State dinner for Their Majesties at the White House, 1977 November 15 (Box 219, Folder 4-5)
    - Reception following Their Imperial Majesties' state visit, 1977 November (Box 219, Folder 6-8)
    - Howard University dinner at the Embassy, 1977 December 2 (Box 219, Folder 9-10)
      Includes photographs of Kessi and Paul Bomani, Maureen Bunyan, Dr. and Mrs. James Cheek, William Thaddeus Coleman Jr., Chester Davenport, Francis Alfonso William Dennis, Dennis O. Green, Donald Hense, Mr. and Mrs. Sanford McDonnell, and Dr. Charles Williams.
    - Black tie dinner for Governor and Mrs. Ronald Reagan, 1977 December 15 (Box 219, Folder 11-13)
      Includes photographs of Barbara and Joe Allbritton, Deeda Blair, William Blair, Aldred and Betsy Bloomingdale, Wiley Buchanan, Claudette Colbert, Janet Hooker, Slim Keith, Nan Kempner, Mr. and Mrs. James Kilpatrick, Mr. and Mrs. Austin H. Kiplinger, Paul Laxalt, John Willard Marriott, John McCain, Mary McGrory, Aileen Mehle, Harry Platt, Helen and William Safire, Richard Schweiker, Earl Smith, Mike Wallace, and Lynn Wyatt.
    - Ambassador Zahedi's interview by Mr. Gerald Green, Washington editor of Military Electronics Countermeasures, 1977 December 16 (Box 220, Folder 1)
    - Black tie dinner for His Excellency and Mrs. Mohammad Yeganeh, 1978 February 27 (Box 220, Folder 2-5)
      Includes photographs of W. Michael Blumenthal, Mr. and Mrs. Harold Crosby, Cloris Leachman, Jermaine and Warren Magnuson, Pat Mitchell, Charles Naas, Sam Nunn, Kermit Roosevelt Jr., Mr. and Mrs. Marvin Stone, William H. Sullivan, and Cyrus and Grace Vance.
    - Farewell reception for Dr. and Mrs. Abbas Ordoobadi, 1978 March 3 (Box 220, Folder 6-8)
      Includes photographs of Cecil Andrus, Elgin Groseclose, and Ibrahim Pourhadi.
    - Black tie dinner for General Gholam Reza Azhari and Lieutenant General Nasser Moghadam, 1978 April 7 (Box 220, Folder 9-11)
      Includes photographs of Clifford Alexander, Barbara and William Colby, Douglas MacArthur, and Khadijeh Pirnia.
    - Cocktails for Miss Beverly Sills, 1978 May 3 (Box 220, Folder 12-13)
      Includes photographs of Martin Agronsky, François Lefebvre de Laboulaye, and Søren Christian Sommerfelt.
    - Buffet dinner for members of the International Management and Development Institute, 1978 May 19 (Box 221, Folder 1)
    - Reception for the Capitol Children's Museum, 1978 May 21 (Box 221, Folder 2)
    - Informal dinner for His Excellency Ahmad Ali Ahmadi, 1978 June 2 (Box 221, Folder 3-4)
    - Informal dinner for Mr. and Mrs. George Allen, 1978 June 16 (Box 221, Folder 5-6)
    - Barbeque and swimming in honor of the Capitol Children's Museum at Zahedi's residence, 1978 July 22 (Box 221, Folder 7-8)
      Includes photographs of Farahnaz, Ali-Reza, and Laila Pahlavi.
    - Farewell reception for the Tavallalis, Ardalans, and Safinyas, 1978 August 17 (Box 221, Folder 9-12)
    - Black tie dinner for His Excellency Dr. Mohammad Yeganeh, 1978 September 16 (Box 221, Folder 13)
    - Informal dinner, 1978 October 26 (Box 222, Folder 1)
      Includes photographs of Reza Pahlavi and Zbigniew Brzezinski.
    - Dinner on the occasion of His Imperial Highness Crown Prince Reza's birthday, 1978 October 30 (Box 222, Folder 2-4)
      Includes photographs of Jimmy Carter.
  - Ambassador albums, 1970-1978
    Albums appear to contain highlights from Zahedi's time as ambassador, as many of the events are also represented in other albums and photograph groups. Some of the photographs are also duplicated within these other groups. The original numbering of the albums is maintained.
    The following people appear in multiple albums: Hushang Ansary, Pearl Bailey, Bunny and Philip W. Buchen, Huang Chen, Deena Clark, Joanne Herring, Henry and Nancy Kissinger, Adele and William P. Rogers, and Bonnie and John Swearingen.
    - Album 1, 1970, 1973-1974 (Box 222, Folder 5-6)
      Includes photographs of Judy and Spiro Agnew, David Bruce, Arlene Dahl, Joan Fontaine, Barry Goldwater, Henry M. Jackson, Sultan Mohammed Khan, Mohammad Khatami, Mara and Sylvan Marshall, Liza Minnelli, Carlos Manuel Muñiz, Julie Newmar, Richard Nixon, Farah and Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, and Mariano Rumor.
    - Album 2, 1974 (Box 223, Folder 1, Box 222, Folder 7-8)
      Includes photographs of İhsan Sabri Çağlayangil, Fleur Cowles, Joan Fontaine, Betty and Gerald Ford, Ashraf Ghorbal, Sahabzada Yaqub Khan, Alice Roosevelt Longworth, Pat and Richard Nixon, Frances and Peter Ramsbotham, Badreddine Senoussi, and Shirley Temple.
    - Album 3, 1974 (Box 223, Folder 2-3)
      Includes photographs of Huang Chen, Rodger Davies, Gerald Ford, Lady Bird Johnson, Giovanni Leone, Richard Nixon, Glenn A. Olds, Léopold Sédar Senghor, and Kurt Walhdeim.
    - Album 4, 1974-1975 (Box 223, Folder 4-5)
      Includes photographs of Betty and Gerald Ford, King Hussein and Queen Alia, and David Rockefeller.
    - Album 5, 1975 (Box 223, Folder 6, Box 224, Folder 1-2)
      Includes photographs of Fawzia, Margot Fonteyn, Han Hsu, Rose Kennedy, Edward Kennedy, Abdullah Saleh Al Mana, Rudolf Nureyev, Shams Pahlavi, Nelson Rockefeller, Kermit Roosevelt Jr., Sultan bin Muhammad Al-Qasimi, Barbra Streisand, and Mahnaz Zahedi.
    - Album 6, 1975-1976 (Box 224, Folder 3-4)
      Includes photographs of Nusrat and Zulfikar Ali Bhutto, Ashraf Pahlavi, Anwar Sadat, Barbara Walters, and John Wayne.
    - Album 7, 1976 (Box 225, Folder 1, Box 224, Folder 5-6)
      Includes photographs of Queen Alia of Jordan, Barnee Breeskin, Manouchehr Eghbal, Philip Habib, Mike Mansfield, Catherine Aleya Sursock, Elizabeth Taylor, and Mahnaz Zahedi.
    - Album 8, 1976-1977 (Box 225, Folder 2-3)
      Includes photographs of Jimmy and Rosalynn Carter, Bob and Elizabeth Dole, Ashraf Ghorbal, Shams Pahlavi, José López Portillo, and Anwar Sadat.
    - Album 9, 1977-1978 (Box 226, Folder 1, Box 225, Folder 4-5)
      Includes photographs of Jimmy and Rosalynn Carter, Eva Gabor, King Hussein of Jordan, Farah and Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, Nancy and Ronald Reagan, Elizabeth Taylor, Barbara Walters, and Cyrus Vance.
  - Nowruz albums, 1973-1975
    Consists of albums depicting Zahedi celebrating Nowruz with different Iranian groups throughout the United States. Many of the albums were gifted to him by these groups.
    - Party, undated (Box 226, Folder 2-3)
    - Los Angeles, undated (Box 226, Folder 4)
      Includes photographs of Pearl Bailey.
    - New York City, 1973 March (Box 226, Folder 5)
    - Washington, D.C., 1973 March (Box 226, Folder 6-7)
      Includes photographs of Abdullah Malikyar, Sylvan Marshall, Mansur Rafizadeh, and Firooz Zahedi.
    - Iranian Students Association, Southern California-Los Angeles, 1974 March (Box 227, Folder 1)
    - Iranian Student Association, Chicago, 1974 March (Box 227, Folder 2-3)
    - Society of Iranians in San Francisco, 1974 March (Box 227, Folder 4-5)
    - Society of Iranians in New York, 1974 March (Box 228, Folder 1-3)
      Includes photographs of Daryoush Homayoun and Gholam H. Kazemian.
    - Sheraton-Park Hotel, Washington, D.C., 1974 March 20 (Box 228, Folder 4-6, Box 229, Folder 1)